<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>secxbrl.info - US Public Company Financial Information Repository</title><link href="https://app.secxbrl.info/blog/atom.xml"/><updated>2014-06-05T20:26:38.872164+02:00</updated><author><name>28msec</name></author><entry><title>28msec and Rivet Software Announcing Strategic Partnership</title><id>/87909746105/28msec-and-rivet-software-announcing-strategic-partnership</id><summary>We are extremely excited to announce a strategic partnership between 28msec and Rivet Software. Rivet Software is an industry leader in financial reporting.</summary><updated>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 13:59:00 -0400</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are extremely excited to announce a strategic partnership between &lt;a href="http://www.28.io"&gt;28msec&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.rivetsoftware.com"&gt;Rivet Software&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt; Rivet Software is an industry leader in financial reporting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;The partnership will benefit international regulatory agencies and private multi-national companies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;We believe that Rivet&amp;#8217;s Crossfire Solution is the perfect front-end to our powerful information repository.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;For more information, please refer to the official press release: &lt;a href="http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/rivet-and-28msec-to-debut-joint-global-solution-at-xbrl-international-next-week-261828631.html" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/rivet-and-28msec-to-debut-joint-global-solution-at-xbrl-international-next-week-261828631.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.28.io" title="28.io" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://31.media.tumblr.com/8b0782a6f3c88e6b251a1e16a1354df8/tumblr_inline_n6m5juD65a1spqbuk.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rivetsoftware.com" title="Rivet Software" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://31.media.tumblr.com/97727061f9ceba898740c29b2116a4e0/tumblr_inline_n6m5kaUnLT1spqbuk.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category label="xbrl"/><category label="secxbrl"/></entry><entry><title>secxbrl.info: One Step Forward</title><id>/86397995485/secxbrlinfo-one-step-forward</id><summary>Ethan Rouen, a Ph.D. candidate in accounting at Columbia Business School, has published an article called "One step backward for corporate accountability". In his article, he talks about the potential of XBRL to revolutionize the way to access and analyze company financial results the instant they became public. However, he claims that the 10-K and 10-Q documents filed by US public companies using XBRL are of embarrassingly poor quality.</summary><updated>Wed, 21 May 2014 07:34:00 -0400</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ethan Rouen, a Ph.D. candidate in accounting at Columbia Business School, has published an article called &lt;a href="http://finance.fortune.cnn.com/2014/04/24/corporate-earnings-disclosure-transparency/" target="_blank"&gt;"One step backward for corporate accountability"&lt;/a&gt;. In his article, he talks about the potential of XBRL to revolutionize the way to access and analyze company financial results the instant they became public. However, he claims that the 10-K and 10-Q documents filed by US public companies using XBRL are of embarrassingly poor quality.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;With secxbrl.info, we are providing a service that makes the consumption and validation of such reports extremely easy. For example, we have recently published a &lt;a href="http://app.secxbrl.info/comparison/validations-dashboard?tag=DOW30&amp;amp;fiscalYear=2013&amp;amp;fiscalPeriod=FY" title="Validation Dashboard" target="_blank"&gt;validation dashboard&lt;/a&gt; that allows business users to assess the consistency, accuracy, and comparability of the information using basic accounting rules. Also, we are happy that we were able to support Ethan doing his research using our platform.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We are looking forward to hear your thoughts on this.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category label="secxbrl"/><category label="xbrl"/></entry><entry><title>Charles Hoffman on secxbrl.info</title><id>/85623075060/charles-hoffman-on-secxbrlinfo</id><summary>Charles Hoffman posted a great article on secxbrl.info.</summary><updated>Tue, 13 May 2014 09:57:55 -0400</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Charles Hoffman posted a &lt;a href="http://xbrl.squarespace.com/journal/2014/5/10/secxbrlinfo-opens-up-new-dimensions-for-testing-sec-financia.html" title="SECXBRL.info Opens Up New Dimensions for Testing SEC Financial Filings" target="_blank"&gt;great article on secxbrl.info&lt;/a&gt;. Specifically, he illustrates how the secxbrl.info API can be used for testing the SEC financial filings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://secxbrl.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/requests/new" title="Contact us" target="_blank"&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt; what you think.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category label="secxbrl"/></entry><entry><title>NoLAP:  Breaking the Curse of Dimensionality</title><id>/85528073805/nolap--breaking-the-curse-of-dimensionality</id><summary>Did you ever wonder how secxbrl.info is able to handle the huge amount of highly-dimensional data? Here is why.</summary><updated>Mon, 12 May 2014 10:54:00 -0400</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Did you ever wonder how &lt;a href="http://secxbrl.info"&gt;secxbrl.info&lt;/a&gt; is able to handle the huge amount of highly-dimensional data? Here is why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many XBRL services providers store XBRL data in a relational database. However, very soon, the limits of homogeneous, flat tables are reached and slow down requests. Other services leverage the fact that the XBRL syntax is based on XML and store it, as is, in an XML database. Yet, the raw XBRL format is not suitable for querying, or at least, for querying with reasonable performance: while XBRL uses the XML syntax, its data model is significantly different from that of XML, in at least the two following ways. If you leave tuples aside, there is nothing flatter than a physical fact. Networks that have no directed cycles (i.e., directed acyclic graphs, often even trees) can be stored in more optimal ways than raw XLink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With NoSQL technologies, XBRL can be stored in an way that is optimized for hypercube querying (we called this &lt;em&gt;NoLAP&lt;/em&gt;). NoLAP extends the OLAP paradigm by removing hypercube rigidity and letting users generate their own hypercubes on the fly on the same pool of (fact) values. Very much like NoSQL technologies extend the SQL paradigm by replacing flat, homogeneous tables with heterogeneous, arborescent data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out all the exciting details and advantages of NoLAP at &lt;a href="http://28.io/nolap" title="NoLAP" target="_blank"&gt;http://28.io/nolap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category label="secxbrl"/></entry><entry><title>Measuring Quality by Verifying Fundamental Accounting Concepts and Relations Between Concepts Using Custom Reports</title><id>/85127528110/measuring-quality-by-verifying-fundamental-accounting-concepts-and-relations-between-concepts-using-custom-reports</id><summary>In this blog entry, we are addressing the following characteristics: Consistency, accuracy, and comparability. Specifically, we show how the custom report feature of secxbrl.info can be used as a framework for building functionality to verify those characteristics.</summary><updated>Thu, 08 May 2014 11:53:00 -0400</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://app.secxbrl.info/"&gt;secxbrl.info&lt;/a&gt; is a complete database of U.S. public company financial information. For such a database to be useful, the information in there has to be of extremely high quality. Generally, any such information has to meet the following characteristics to enable it for mainstream consumption (cf. &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://www.cfapubs.org/toc/ccb/2007/2007/6" title="A Comprehensive Business Reporting Model"&gt;A Comprehensive Business Reporting Model&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221;, CFA Institute, July 2007):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Accurate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Comparable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Timely&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Comprehensive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Complete&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Consistent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Relevant&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;With this article, we are addressing the following characteristics from that list: &lt;strong&gt;Consistency, accuracy, and comparability&lt;/strong&gt;. Specifically, we show how the custom report feature of secxbrl.info can be used as a framework for building functionality to verify those characteristics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Financial filings are rich in relations between facts. In fact, it&amp;#8217;s all about consistency of such relationships. For example, &amp;#8220;Assets = Liabilities and Equity&amp;#8221; is an equality relation between reported facts. That relation is undisputed, it is &amp;#8220;the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accounting_equation" title="Accounting Equation"&gt;accounting equation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. There are many more such undisputed relations (e.g. &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://fundamentalaccountingconcepts.wikispaces.com/" title="Fundamental Accounting Concepts"&gt;Fundamental Accounting Concepts&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;). We leverage such rules to depict how their validation can be used to improve information quality.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Specifically, here is what we did:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Created a report containing 55 Fundamental Accounting Concepts, 13 General Information Concepts, and 4 Computed Ratios which allows for comparing filings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Leveraged mappings (aka synonyms) to overcome situations where different reporting entities are using different US GAAP Taxonomy concepts to report the same information.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Added Business Rules to impute missing values based on information which was reported. For example, if assets was reported and current assets was reported but noncurrent assets was not reported; noncurrent assets can be accurately imputed as being assets - current assets.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Added 23 Validation Rules (with pre-conditions) to verify the accuracy and comparability of the reported and imputed information.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Created a dashboard to see and compare the results of the created validation rules.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validation Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-3c87d1d1-db5c-b11b-a6f4-03a21f7cef44"&gt;The validation dashboard is available on &lt;a href="https://app.secxbrl.info/comparison/validations-dashboard?tag=DOW30&amp;amp;fiscalYear=2013&amp;amp;fiscalPeriod=FY" title="Compare Accuracy Measurements of Basic Financial Information Across Selected Filings"&gt;secxbrl.info&lt;/a&gt;. You can validate any number of filings and investigate the results of all 23 validation rules. Everything you see is computed in real time. Here is the dashboard showing the ranking of the information quality for the 2013&amp;#160;10-K filings of the DOW30 entities:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/lQU0zsi.png" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://31.media.tumblr.com/4b502b883a49e628230a42725cfbc3ff/tumblr_inline_n593n4tgHb1sfxrpi.gif"/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-3c87d1d1-db5e-8574-6322-300b575ccfa0"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Overall, the &amp;#8220;consitency, accuracy, comparability rate&amp;#8221; of each of the DOW30&amp;#8217;s filings (FY 2013) is between 70% and 100%. 6 out of 30 filings have an pass rate of 100%. The information quality in 24 out of 30 filings can be improved.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does it work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-3c87d1d1-db60-4293-4f97-d54bc3b49b59"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Let us explain how a basic validation rule is verified by secxbrl.info. Let&amp;#8217;s take the rule shown above:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://31.media.tumblr.com/f6827d04588270d4949bed652b2b7bfc/tumblr_inline_n593r96Vmx1sfxrpi.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A filer may, or may not, have reported one of those concepts. For example, assets might not have been reported by a filer, but current assets has been instead. In case noncurrent assets doesn&amp;#8217;t exist, we can impute assets from current assets. Correspondingly, we needed to add a set of business rules (including pre-conditions) to accommodate for such situations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Also, filers could have used different concepts to report the same information. For example, liabilities and equity might have been reported using &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;us-gaap:LiabilitiesAndStockholdersEquity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; or &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;us-gaap:LiabilitiesAndPartnersCapital&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. To overcome this, this we added a set of &lt;a href="https://app.secxbrl.info/concept-map/FundamentalAccountingConcepts" title="Fundamental Accounting Concept Mappings"&gt;concept mappings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(aka aliases or synonyms). This allows us to work with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;fac:LiabilitiesAndEquity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; while the system automatically figures out which of the aliases (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;us-gaap:LiabilitiesAndStockholdersEquity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; or &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;us-gaap:LiabilitiesAndPartnersCapital&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;) has effectively been reported.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the following, we illustrate all the rules of the balance sheet:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://31.media.tumblr.com/190c742a7e5a621ca2f5ce7f61da9559/tumblr_inline_n5949wHWmo1sfxrpi.png"/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;Custom Reports is a General Tool&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The way information is reported in SEC filings varies significantly. Custom reports are a general tool allowing users to compare such information (leveraging synonyms and business rules). One application of such a report is the validation dashboard introduced in this article. However, that&amp;#8217;s not the only application of custom reports. Other applications are&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Compare information if it is comparable and drill down functionality to analyze less comparable detailed information.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Impute information that is not explicitly part of a filing but can be derived from other information reported in a filing (e.g. ratios).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Create timelines of single company or sector information.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Slicing and Dicing the data in order to extract relevant information that meets your needs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-3c87d1d1-db6b-7ae6-22be-c6747e67a3fb"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In general, custom reports empower business users with powerful and useful functionality.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category label="secxbrl"/></entry><entry><title>Launch of SECXBRL.info, powered by 28.io</title><id>/81678006917/launch-of-secxbrlinfo-powered-by-28io</id><summary>We are excited to announce a new way you to explore financial and business information: secxbrl.info.</summary><updated>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 09:48:00 -0400</updated><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SEC XBRL financial filing guessing game is over! You can do this for any concept, any axis. Point&amp;#8230; click&amp;#8230; ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Charles Hoffman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce a new way to explore financial and business information: &lt;a href="http://secxbrl.info" title="US Public Company Financial Information Repository" target="_blank"&gt;secxbrl.info&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The financial crisis of 2008 made it clear to everybody what happens if important financial information is not readily accessible in an accurate, timely, easy-to-use, and affordable manner. On January 30, 2009, the SEC issued rules mandating public companies to provide their financial statement information using the eXtensible Business Reporting Language (&amp;#8220;XBRL&amp;#8221;) interactive data format. Yet, even four years later, in December 2012, Suzanne Morsfield and Trevor Harris had to state in a widely-read report that &amp;#8220;without a serious reconsideration of the technology, coupled with a focus on facile usability of the data, and value-add consumption tools, it will at best remain of marginal benefit to the target audience of both its early proponents and the SEC&amp;#8217;s mandate - investors and analysts.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2014, &lt;a href="http://28msec.com" target="_blank"&gt;28msec&lt;/a&gt; launched &lt;a href="http://secxbrl.info" title="US Public Company Financial Information Repository" target="_blank"&gt;secxbrl.info&lt;/a&gt;, a technological breakthrough that is delivering XBRL&amp;#8217;s promise. Or as Charles Hoffman, co-inventor of XBRL, puts it: &amp;#8220;The SEC XBRL financial filing guessing game is over!&amp;#8221; Designed as a service to provide access to financial information the way it should be, &lt;a href="http://secxbrl.info" title="US Public Company Financial Information Repository" target="_blank"&gt;secxbrl.info&lt;/a&gt; enables flexible, ad-hoc, and real-time analysis of all yearly (10-K) and quarterly (10-Q) financial reports of US public companies that have been submitted to the SEC since 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://secxbrl.info" target="_blank"&gt;secxbrl.info&lt;/a&gt; is powered by the game-changing 28.io information processing platform. The platform leverages powerful NoSQL technologies such that XBRL-based information can be stored in a way that is optimized for querying (aka &lt;a href="http://28.io/xbrl"&gt;NOLAP: NoSQL Analytical Processing&lt;/a&gt;). This allows for virtually limitless customization and even for turning it into your own private business reporting solution tailored to your specific analytical needs and using your own XBRL-based information. Learn more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category label="secxbrl"/><category label="xbrl"/></entry></feed>